J.D. Fillmore

jd@jdfill.me | (289) 213 - 3368 | https://jdfill.me | https://github.com/jd-fillmore

CAREER PROFILE

Front-end developer with 7 years experience in developing functional, accessible websites and web applications for in-house corporations and clients. Experienced in leading projects from concept to launch as well as mentoring junior front-end developers.

Experienced in React, React Hooks, TypeScript, Styled Components, JavaScript (ES5/6), JavaScript Front-End Frameworks, Functional Programming, Storybook, GraphQL, REST APIs (JSON, Fetch API, Axios), GatsbyJS, NextJS, JAMStack, Content Management Systems, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Flexbox, Bootstrap, Netlify, Git, Version Control, Testing / Debugging, Responsive / Mobile Design, Adobe XD, Adobe Photoshop, Sketch, InVision, SEO, WCAG / AODA AA Accessibility, Agile

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

- Development efforts directly generated over \$4,000,000 in revenue over one month during the height of the COVID-19 pandemic for Battlefield Equipment Rentals
- Contributed to a web application on the front-end which was used by 14,000,000 people worldwide
- Catered to persons with disabilities through having programmed accessible websites and web applications
- Have worked alongside industry giants such as Tim Hortons and PC Financial

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Front-End Developer, Team Lead | Battlefield Equipment Rentals (Toromont Cat) | Remote Dec. 2019 - Present Administer and integrate features to React & TypeScript web application, lead all web projects.

- Code & design national product landing pages, achieving \$3,000,000 in revenue in May 2020 during COVID-19
- Maintain and implement features to a React & TypeScript web application, generating over \$1,000,000 of revenue within the first month
- Implement dynamic product filtering and image categorization to web application increasing user experience

Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer, Project Manager | Freelance Consultant | Remote April 2013 - Present Design & build modern websites using React (GatsbyJS), manage clients, build web applications for learning purposes.

- 60% increase in all clients overall local SEO rankings due to accessibility, speed, user experience & performance
- Notable side clients Cass-A-Bella Construction, KD Flowers, MC Aesthetics React / Gatsby-based websites
- Featured pet projects Maple Leafs Stats, Movie Database React-based web apps with API integration

Front-End Developer (Contract) | VelocityEHS | Oakville, ON

June 2019 - Dec. 2019

Developed UI features to the front-end of React web application,, team lead for accessibility, mentored junior developers.

- Added UI features to new React v6 web app, increasing accessibility and user experience for persons with disabilities by 100%
- AODA accessibility team lead, mentored and educated internal team (2 UX designers / 2 frontend developers)
- Constructed Storybook reusable code component library, decreased development time by over 50%
- Conducted and participated in code reviews, reduced errors by 50%

Front-End Developer | Thrillworks | Burlington, ON

April 2018 - June 2019

Constructed modern websites using React (GatsbyJS) and worked with clients such as Tim Hortons and PC Financial.

- Crafted reusable code component library, decreasing development time by over 60%
- One of four leading members of the AODA AA Accessibility Board, educated internal staff on accessibility

Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer, Project Manager | Virtual Image | Hamilton, ON Sept. 2016 - April 2018 Designed and created content management websites as well as managed client projects from start to finish.

- 60% decrease in development time of websites due to component based libraries
- Created client designs increasing user engagement and experience by 120% compared to old websites
- Local SEO efforts leading to a 70% increase in local Google client rankings

Front-End Developer (Contract) | Elite Digital | Toronto, ON

March 2016 - Sept. 2016

Front-End Developer, UI / UX Designer | iOPW | Toronto, ON

Aug. 2014 - March 2016

EDUCATION

Durham College, Oshawa, ON | Advanced Diploma in Multimedia Design